<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Technical Fun</title>
    <link href="https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.ehosted.co.uk" />
    <updated>2022-09-07T16:12:27+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Dave</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.ehosted.co.uk</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Bedrock Server</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/bedrock-server.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/bedrock-server.html</id>

        <updated>2022-09-07T16:12:27+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This is hosted in my office (Read Converted Garedn Shed) and is an old Dell Inspirion 13 laptop repurposed with&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This is hosted in my office (Read Converted Garedn Shed)  and is an old Dell Inspirion 13 laptop repurposed with Windows 2022 Server and run Bedrock Dedicated Server ( Which you can download <a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/download/server/bedrock" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> ) </p>
<figure class="post__image align-center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/media/posts/2/PXL_20220901_100256048.MP2569.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/media/posts/2/responsive/PXL_20220901_100256048.MP2569-xs.jpg 300w ,https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/media/posts/2/responsive/PXL_20220901_100256048.MP2569-sm.jpg 480w ,https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/media/posts/2/responsive/PXL_20220901_100256048.MP2569-md.jpg 768w"  alt="" width="4080" height="3072"></figure>
<p>The Spec of the machine has 16GB Ram and and older Intel I5. </p>
<p>The Bedrock Server is pretty much a vanilla install with a couple of additions. The first is a quality of life installation of<a href="https://foxynotail.com/add-ons/ops/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> One Player Sleep from Foxy No Tail</a> and <a href="https://foxynotail.com/software/mcbe-play/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Foxys Bedrock Server Software</a> , with  some script for backups and map building (<a href="https://unmined.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Unmined.net</a>). </p>
<p>Backup are done through the Windows Drive Snapshot feature that allows Windows to save change only data, thus keeping backups smaller and allow 15 mins snapshots to be taken. </p>
<p>Mapping is an important part of any Minecraft server and Bedrock has suffered from a lack of tooling to automate this process. Unmined fixes this to some degree as it allows both Java and Bedrock Servers to either be viewed through a GUI or can produce a Web based map for deployment via a Web server. </p>
<p>Once Unmined has created its map this uploaded to GitHub and then pushed to Cloudflares Static Website host which offers free Site hosting for static files. This process can be seen in more details on the GitHub Page. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Minecraft Setup</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/the-minecraft-setup.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/the-minecraft-setup.html</id>

        <updated>2022-09-01T11:57:41+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This post is to try and document all the different way I play and host minecraft servers so that i&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This post is to try and document all the different way I play and host minecraft servers so that i dont forget what i have done as time moves on. I play mainly Minecraft Bedrock edition but have recently switched between Java and Bedrock. This is primarily do to the Geyser plugins that allows Bedrock clients to connect to Java servers. </p>
<p>Each of the links below will go into what kit i have, how i use each of them, and what config/ setup i have on each. </p>
<p>What do i currently have and what do i play on:</p>
<p>Xbox Series X   ( Minecraft Bedrock) </p>
<p>Windows 11 - Dell G15 Gaming Laptop </p>
<p>Pixel 6Pro - Bedrock and occasional Proxy </p>
<p><a href="https://blog.ehosted.co.uk/bedrock-server.html">Dell Inspirion - Bedrock Server</a></p>
<p>Raspberry Pi - Phantom and Java/ Bedrock server ( small scale) </p>
<p>Oracle Cloud ARM Server - Current Skyblock server</p>
<p>GitHub - Code repositories </p>
<p>Cloudflare - DDOS protection and Staic Site Hosting </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
